Guide to the Benjamin D. Paul Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Benjamin D. Paul papers
1941-2000
SC0741
Paul, Benjamin D., (Benjamin David), 1911-
30 Linear feet
Papers include field notes from research trips to Guatemala, 1941-2000; other research files and notes, including some of his wife Lois Paul; correspondence; class files and departmental records; and reprints.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
Access: Collection is unprocessed; please consult with the University Archivist for access.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Benjamin D. Paul joined the Stanford faculty in 1963; he held bachelor's and doctoral degrees from the University of Chicago. He directed the Program in Medicine and the Behavioral Sciences from 1963 to 1971 and was chairman of the Department of Anthropology from 1967 to 1971. He made numerous field trips to the highlands of Guatemala (many with his wife Lois), living with and studying the Maya Indians of San Pedro la Laguna on Lake Atitlan.
Description of the Collection
Papers include field notes from research trips to Guatemala, 1941-2000; other research files and notes, including some of his wife Lois Paul; correspondence; class files and departmental records; and reprints.
Access Terms
Paul, Benjamin D., (Benjamin David), 1911-; Paul, Benjamin D., Mrs.; Paul, Lois.; Stanford University. Department of Anthropology.; Anthropology--Study and teaching.; Guatemala --Social life and customs.
Collection Contents
- Papers, Accession ARCH-2003-186
  - Field notes: A – Pol. Org. II
    Note: box 1 also contains Outline of Cultural Materials: a working manual prepared for emergency use by the Cross-Cultural Survey and the Stategic Index of the Americas from Yale University AND B.D. Paul's Annotations
    - Microfilm Preface and Table of Contents (original) San Pedro la Laguna: B.D. Paul (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Outlines – San Pedro monograph (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Microfilms: facesheets and preface (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1-90 Afflictions (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 91-187 Animals I (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 188-288 Animals II (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 289-341.4 Biog. [Chema] (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 342-396 Biog. (Eng) Desiderio (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 342-405.6 Biog. Des. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 406-484 Biog. Raf. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 485-542 Biog. Vic.-Bixcul (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 543-570 Budgets (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 571-610 Census Data I (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Census Data II (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 611-650.28 Childhood I (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 651-680 Childhood II (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Child Dev, Training, Etc. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - 681-704.6 Cliques (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - 705-850 Crops (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - 851-902 Death (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - 903-967 Deviants I (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - 968-1032 Deviants II (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - 1033-1099 Deviants III (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - 1100-1147 Deviants IV (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - 1148-1194.4 Deviants V (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - MS. L.P. Deviants (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - 1195-1236 Dreams (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - 1237-1257 Houses (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - 1258-1317 Housekeeping (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - MS. L.P. House and Contents (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - 1318-1408 Human Body (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - 1409-1432 Hunting (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - 1433-1458 Kinship I (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Kinship II Misc. and Dup. B.D. Paul (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Kinship III – Rosales (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - 1459-1524 Military (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - 1525-1550 Names I (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Naming II – Edmonson (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - 1551-1611 Nature (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - 1612-1666 Outgroups (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - 1667-1735 Outgroups (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - 1736-1859 Plants (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - 1860-1933 Pol. Org. I (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - 1934-2056 Pol. Org. II (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Field notes: Pol. Org. III – Diary RAF III
    - 2057-2144 Pol. Org. III (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Pol. Org. IV, B.D.P.'s chart, etc. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - 2145-2290 Principales (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - 2291-2361 Prop. And Wealth I (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - 2362-2519 Prop. And Wealth II (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - 2520-2600 Prop. And Wealth III (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - 2601-2744 Protestant I (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Protestant II (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - 2745-2857 Religion I (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - 2858-2977 Religion II (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - 2978-3057.36 Religion III (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - 3058-3146 Religion IV (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - 3084-3124 Manuel [G2] 42-5-15 Fiesta S Pedro, Span., 41 pp. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - 3147-3304 Religion V (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Religion VI, Lopez: Relacion Hist. De las actividades de la Parroguia (1960) (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - 3305-3384 Reproduction I (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - 3385-3436.8 Reproduction II (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Reproduction IV, Midwives (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - 3437-3566 Sex-Marriage I (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - 3634-3709.2 Sex-Marriage III (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Sex-Marriage IV, Letters MS.-BDP. Orig. Elopement Paper (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - 3710-3749 Specialists (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - 3750-3841 Stories (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - 3842-3954 Supernatural (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - 3955-4058 Diary B.P. Jan. (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - 4059-4236 Diary B.P. Feb. (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - 4237-4378 Diary B.P. Mar. (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - 4379-4455 Diary B.P. Apr. I (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - 4456-4556 Diary B.P. Apr. II (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - 4557-4576 Diary B.P. May (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - 4577-4629 Diary B.P. June (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - 4630-4640 Diary B.P. July (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - 4641-4691 Diary B.P. Aug. (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - 4692-4737 Diary B.P. Sept. (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - 4738-4851 Diary Chema I, English Summaries And Orig. (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - 4852-4922 Diary Chema II (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - 4923-4963 Diary Raf. I. English Summaries and Dup. (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - 4964-5056 Diary Raf. II (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - 5057-5168 Diary Raf. III (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Field notes: Diary RAF IV – Misc 39.4
    - 5169-5252 Diary Raf. IV (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - 5253-5339 Diary Raf. V (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Diaries Misc. Vic., Des., Tono Pedro Susana (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Rosales Demandas I (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Rosales Demandas II (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Rosales Demandas III (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Rosales Demandas IV (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Rosales Demandas V (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Rosales Demandas VI (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - MS. L.P. Biog. Des. Trans. Includes: autobiog. and misc. documents (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Biog. Des. Trans. Copy 2 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Technology Tiles, Fishing (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Psychoculture (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Misc. S.P. 1941 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Zutuhil - Language (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Language – Cak., Maya, Gen'l. (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - S.P. in Outline BDP [lecture] (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence – Redfield Tax, Rosales, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Misc. Inf. – Other Guat. Towns: S.A. Palopo, Nahuala, San Luis Jil. (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Zutuhil History I: "Indios de Atitlan," Lothrop, Recinos, Vasquez, etc. (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Zutuhil History II (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Zutuhil History III L.P. (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Memos, Orig. 1941 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Exhibits – Misc. 1941, Cath. Calendar, Old Skirt Material (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Exhibits Drawings 1941 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Carbons – SP Notes I (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Carbons – Notes II (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Map – L. Atitlan and Environs, Map of Maya Region (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Diary Jan. Dup. 1 and 2, San Pedro: 1 set (and duplicate of 3 small items) (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Diary Feb. Dup. 1 and 2 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Diary Mar. Dup. 1 and 2 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Diary Apr. Dup. 1 and 2 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Diary May Dup. 1 and 2 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Correspondence 1941-42, Letters to Folks (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Corres. - S.P. 1941-1942 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Misc. 39, ‘A' (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Anthropology Department materials and other items, including papers by Lois Paul and others
    - S.U. grad student financial support 1 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - S.U. grad student financial support 2 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Anth. Budget: 50-50% H and S (and gifts) (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Anth. Dept. Budget 2001 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - R. Sage "Endocument" IEB2-201-11 "Pool B" (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - S.U. grad student financial support 3 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - S.U. grad student financial support 4 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Anth. Grads: Misc. (residual, 6/77) (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Anth. Grads: Sum. Support: 1976-77 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Anth. Grads: Backstopping memos, 1975-1977 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Anth. Grads: Summ 1975-76 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Anth. Budget: S. & E. (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Anth. Budget: Secretaries (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Anth. Budget: hard-soft ratio sheets (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Anth. Budget: 50-50 Grad. Div. etc. (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - National Institute of General Medical Sciences (NIGMS)-National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH) stuff (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Anth. Grads: Costs (var. categories) (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Anth. Grads: Funding Success/Failure records (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Committee on Student Finance 1978 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Russell Sage: EAB 601 and EAB 607 and RS correspondence, Foundation Fund (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Barnett, Clifford R. Recommendation for appointment, spring 1964 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Personnel (Sal., FBI, Benefits, etc.) (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - BDP (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - NIGMS 05 (extended thru 06 year) (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - NIGMS 01~04 (dead drawer) awards, reports, etc. (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - NIGMS-06 Functional (phase-out names, dates) (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - NIGMS-07 (1974-75) I-EBZ-565 (teaching) (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - NIGMS-08 (1975-76) (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - NIGMS-09 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - NIGMS-10 (1977-78) (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - NIMH-11 (1972-73) (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - NIMH-12 (1973-74) (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - NIMH-13 (1974-75) (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - NIMH-14 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - NIMH-15 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - NIMH-16 data for renewal (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - AES 1982 Budgeting Statements (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - AES 1983 Budget and Statements (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - AES 1983 Bills (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Grad student miscellany (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Miscellanous – antro items, corresondence, biographical (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Miscellaneous – correspondence, student papers, Xeroxed articles (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Papers by other (some for session in memory of Michelle Rosaldo 1982) (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Miscellaneous – mostly papers by others (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Papers by others (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Nadelson, Leslee, "The Origin of the Men's House" 1979 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Miscellanous – "Theoretical Contributions of B.D. Paul"; letter by Paul 1981 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Anth. Grads: Rosters, Lists, Costs (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - BDP, Dept. of Anthro. (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Corresp. CR Barnett 11/78- (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Papers by others (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Papers and notes (Lois Paul?) re midwives in San Pedro (and possibly other topics) (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Paper by Gary Gossen 1973; miscellaneous note cards (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Lois Paul – papers on midwives (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Lois Paul's files on midwives and other subjects
    Note: box 5 also contains a plaque from Stanford Anthropological Society
    - Reproduction III, L.P. MS. also Infancy MS. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Symbolism, Sex, Birth (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Lois Paul, Midwife MS. original (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Lois Paul: "The Changing Role of the Midwife in San Pedro la Laguna, a Guatemalan Indian Community on Lake Atitlan" (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Papers by other people
    - Household papers, Macedonia (E.A. Hammel) and Guatemala (Gross) (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Papers on Shamanism (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Orellana, Sandy (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Papers re medicine (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Personal correspondence file
    - Corr.- Elena's Maestro Son (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Class file
    - Papers and comments, misc. notes, Anth. 226 Spring 1973 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence files
    - Lois Paul, Guat. Correspondence, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Corresp: Demarest, Guat. Res. 1977, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Corresp. A-J (1976-1977) (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Corresp. K-P (1976-78) (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Corresp. R-Z (!976-78) (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Files re 1946 work
    - Guat. Project Reports 1946 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - 1946 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous research files
    - Comparative (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - AAA chgs. 11/18-22/87 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - SP Health Proj.: Data (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Cul. Change – Misc. Lecture Notes (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - SP Change PP and Comments 1969 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Mss Religion II: Guat. 12/73 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Guat. Field Training, Summer ‘69 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Notebooks on anthropology courses
    - SP notes, Stanford University, 1972-3 (1 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - SP notes, Stanford University, 1972-3 (2 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Ben Paul's dissertation
    - Ph.D. Dissertation, U Chicago, 1942. "Godparenthood in Middle America." Original. (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - framed certificate
    - Lois Paul Memorial Fund (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Reprints (Box 6)
  - Ritual Kinship
  - Bibliographic note cards (Box 7)
  - 1 miscellaneous file (Box 7)
  - Scrapbook on ulcers (Box 7)
  - Audio interviews, some transcribed (Box 7)
    - A: Hector- transcription in progress; Aug 2, 94 Hector (z on new Beneficio) - continues on separate cassette, 1994; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 22)
    - A: Matias 7/25/91 trans to 97 to cont; B: Not used., 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 22)
    - Side B, blank (Side A erasable: transcribed: Agapito GzRz), 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 22)
    - A: 11-8-86 1-280+ Miguel Cumatz & son 1-280 (rest, blank); B: 11/9/86 Pablo Cox Matzar & grddau: Protest in 1-540, 540 on blank., 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 22)
    - 7 Jan 95: Samil on Julian's conversn. (obverse is blank), 1995; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 22)
    - 1st Int. Santos 25 July 95, 1995; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 22)
    - Taped Salv's unexpected long visit Sun Aug 7, 94. To listen to but not to transcribe (info for general)., 1994; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 22)
    - Antonio Chavajay Yojcom 1-26-93, 1993; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 7, 22)
    - 3/1/91 2-3 PM Bartolo Chav (this side only) to trans, 1991; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 22)
    - A: 2/19/91 Raf Gz Chr, pintor (continues over) transcribed;B: 2/19/91 Pedro Raf. Gz Chv pintor cont'd transcribed., 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 22)
    - A: 2/7/88 Ant Batz. Econ hist (incomplete) transcribed, discardable; B: 2/9/88 2nd cont Batz 1-470 only., 1988; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 22)
    - Int J Ant Chr Pop to transcribe for 165 onward, 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 22)
    - A: 11-5-86 1-285 Chema el Alto, Prot. capillas; 285 on: part of conf. w/ 3 members of Instituto Basico Committee (last part unrecorded); B: 11-6-86 Pedro Cox (+grandson's wife Jna Raxic) nearly useless., 1986; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 22)
    - P. Raf. GzChr 25 Jan 92 On why he points; transcribed, reusable., 1992; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 22)
    - Belle 7/26/93, 1993; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 7, 22)
    - A: Chema Gz Cox, transcribed 1/29/93 - to reuse; B: 2 Aug 94 Pt 2 Hector Gz (1/2 a ribbon), 1994; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 22)
    - A: 3/3/91 Felipe Char. Pamaxan etc. This side only; B: Mariano cont'd & end to transcribe., 1991; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 22)
    - A: 4/28/89 Roland Cotiec to 450...Victor to 475 (only); B: 4/28/89 Ant Max Chav., 1989; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 22)
    - A: 10-19-88 Chico Mendoza Cotuc: adequately transcribed - erasable, to 425; B: Felipe Chr lxt 10-20-88 one full side., 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 22)
    - 12-15-94 Artist Ant. Yoj. Ch. to transcribe., 1994; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 22)
    - A: 2/7/88 Wicho Botz comments on Ms. Clear; B: 2nd side of 2/4/88 Jant Chv Pop Unt (K's side A inadvertantly erased!) fri 2/7 Wieko., 1988; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 22)
    - A: 10-18-88 Wicho Batz (land switch; identify) - full tape/transcribed, check to reuse; B: Trans only to 165, Andres Chav Gz 10-24-88 Barrios' land switch, Mandamiento ardors. Gz ancestry 300-582., 1988; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 22)
    - A: 10-19-88 Mardoqueo Pop (1 full side); B: Yg Bartolo Cox Estevan 26 Jan 92 Coffee., 1988-1992; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 22)
    - A: Bartolo 27 Jan 92 Under 1/2 a reel; B: Chema Gz Cox (#3) 26 Jan 92., 1992; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 22)
    - A: 2/2/88 Ag Pop: transcribed, erasable 1-600; B: 2/9/88 Alej Mz (part of reel)., 1988; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 22)
    - A: 11-9-86 PM Ant Batts on Prot. growth & splits - all (also B); B: 11-9-86 PM Batts cont'd., 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 22)
    - A: 11-9-86 Abel Ant Bixcul - all; B: 11/10 Pedro Rcc Bx - all., 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 7, 22)
    - A: 8/6/91 Mig Angel Bx (videotape); B: 8/6/91 Ag-video-how it was., 1991; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 22)
    - A: 1993 begins recent Mardo/later: Alto Chema? to trans., 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 7, 22)
    - A: Felipe Chav 1xt. 16 Jan 92 1- 250 to transcribe: Taped only 2nd part of interview., 1992; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 22)
    - A: San Pedro la Laguna Solola, Nicolas Matzar Qulacain; B: San Antonio suchitepequez, Pablo Zapaluta Suhul., 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 22)
    - A: 11/12/86 Lencho Gz, Alc Anon - all., 1986; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 22)
    - A: 11-9-86 AM Luis Mendez: early bakers (all)., 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 22)
    - A: Pedro Chav of Ixmucane 11 Jan 92; B: Mig Angel Bix (II) 21 Jan 92 Protestantism., 1992; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 7, 22)
    - A: 10-20-88 Samuel Cotuc G (cont'd over); B: cont'd Samuel Cotuc G 10/20/80 (partial)., 1988; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 22)
    - A: 2/15/88 Ag Prp on Behrhorst etc 1-550; B: Felipe Chv 2/10/88 Good interview hist of S Juan 110 / why Level was killed., 1988; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 22)
    - A: 10-17-88 Emilio Batz, pastor. Bethel; B: Emilio Batz 10/17/88 (side 2); no trans. either side., 1988; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 23)
    - A: 11/11/86 AM Mardequeo: Regional Pedrano professionals etc. (continues over); B: 11/11/86 Mardequeo (cont'd)., 1986; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 23)
    - A: 2 Feb 93 Mardo (1-450) misc (to transcribe); B: Was Lencho - extesorero/transcribed: to reuse., 1993; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 23)
    - A: 11-10-86 Pancho Yojcom - all (he wants a copy of the tape - "to have Regina hear it"); B: 11/10/86 Rose Chavajay de Par., 1986; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 23)
    - A: Mardoqueo 2/25/91 trans. 1-325, finished 7/2/91; B: Mardo 8/1/91 9 AM 1-360 (old tape thereafter), transcribed 8/2/91., 1991; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 23)
    - A: 7/20 Santos chez moi, casual, to transcribe if data; B: Dionisio Sosa 11 Feb 93, ready to transcribe., 1993; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 23)
    - A: 10-22-88 Pablo Chav. Petzey, nearly full, ends desultorily 500-560, nothing til 600; B: Andres Chv Gz 10-23?-88, partially transcribed - to where tape is., 1988; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 7, 23)
    - A: Salv Q Sac, 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 23)
    - A: J Ant Chav Pop 10-21-88 1-500 (500-600 blank); B: 10-25-88 Agapin (121-215 - tape run on empty & with interruptions and ? 215-600)., 1988; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 23)
    - Kubler, cont'd, 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 23)
    - A: 7/9/98 12 yr old Rosita Nav Rcc w. Morte heavy rain., 1998; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 23)
    - A: July 8 98/Pancho Yojcom, misc; B: July 9, Mauricio's complaint., 1998; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 23)
    - A: 11-2-86 Agapito Cz 1-440, rest is blank, transcribed; B: 11-2 Ag Pop whole tape (transcribed '86 ? 1/28/88)., 1986; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 23)
    - A: Ben - Cult Change 4/28; B: Ben 5/1., 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 23)
    - A: Elena 1/29/75 early life; B: Solala episode worked for captain, courtship + Manuel., 1975; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 23)
    - A: old Raf 2/16/91 concluded (transcribed) - discardable; B: blank., 1991; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 23)
    - A: Elena 2/4; B: blank., 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 23)
    - Side 1: 3/8 Elena; Side 2: Elena., 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 23)
    - A: Bey - cult. change, inst lect; B: blank., 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 23)
    - A: Salv Q Sal - to be trans + Mingo? (trivial); B: Domingo Ga 1-250 (250-270 is morse), P Rafael - 270 on, continuation is transcribed., 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 23)
    - A: San Pedro La Laguna Solola, Nicolas Matzar Quiacain (Part 1); B: Part 2., 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 23)
    - A: 1-165 11/12/86 Santos' music comments, 170-682 11/13 Julio Batzu: his econ hist; B: 11/13/86 short: comments by Santos on released prisoners, overcut by false start: Delfina (to listen & to erase)., 1986; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 23)
    - A: Erasmo Pz 2-8-88 1-2 PM transcribed; B: 2/9/88 Julio Batz 1-2 PM., 1988; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 23)
    - A: 11-6-86 Wisho Batz: context for his Ms on Pascual; B: 11/13/86 1-158 Wicho Batz: more bckgd info on Pascual (mostly blank)., 1986; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 23)
    - A: Elena 2/6/75 charac. + Tono's transfer to GRNA; B: blank., 1975; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 23)
    - A: 11/3/86 Ag II his conversion cont'd 1-733; B: 11/5/86 Ag's comments on today's escrito on Prot. divisions (tape on this had failed)., 1986; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 23)
    - A: 10/30/86 Santos: Moto uses 1-92, German Xet: Catholocism 92-400; B: 10/30/86: Santos: Novena etc. mourning costumbre (1st recording; go to A)., 1986; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 23)
    - A: 11-6-86 Wicho Batz: context for his Ms on Pascual's conversn (4 pp summary 1-88); B: blank., 1986; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 23)
    - A: Usable: has Bart Q 2/6/88 transcribed (B is cont. of " "); B: Usable: has Bart Q 2/6/88 transcribed (partial tape), continuation of A, A is 1st part., 1988; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 23)
    - A: Ag Pop 10/18/88 Lang & Identity (also B); B: Ag Pop 10/18/88 continued - only to #342 (rest is blank)., 1988; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 23)
    - A: 21 July 95 Felipe Shor Int 3, transcribed, but keep; B: blank., 1995; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 23)
    - Side 1: 3/12 S.P. Elena, Francisco Sunu - bonesetter; Side 2: blank., 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 23)
    - A: Tono 2/11; B:Tono 2/13., 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 7, 23)
    - Side 1: 2/19 Elena's house, lunch, Ben, Elena, Juana, mucho? the love letter 004-8--; Side 2: 159-622 2/19/74 Elena, Jesus Q, midwife - love letter., 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 23)
    - A: 7 Feb 8, 93 Mariano, Trans'd 8 Feb - erasable; B: 9 Feb 93 Mardo, misc & not conseq'l, tube transcribed., 1993; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 23)
    - A: Julian Cotuc 3/5/75; B: Col. Pedro Navichoc 3-8-75, 1-830., 1975; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 23)
    - A: Elena 2/7/75; B: blank, not functioning., 1975; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 23)
    - A: Marimba - Ben's birthday, Elena 1/26/74 - child assault; B: birds of Panajachel., 1974; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 23)
    - A: Samil Cc: transcribed, ready to re-use; B: blank., 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 24)
    - Side 1: 2/28 Elena (Panaj) accident bonesetters, Rosario Bx finds money, Susana - begins (50); Side 2: 2/28/74 Elena., 1974; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 24)
    - A: Mig Angel Bx 19 Jan 92 to be trans; B: Chema Gz Cox 20 Jan 92, his life through escapeto, Chiapas (transcribed, but keep?)., 1992; 1 audiocasette(s) (Box 7, 24)